

CURRICULUM VITAE

Paul Pritchard 44 Runswick Road, Bristol, BS4 3HY 07974 442113

makerpaul@gmail.com

Linkedin: <u>linkedin.com/in/paul-pritchard-98713724</u> Github: <u>github.com/kitespin?tab=repositories</u>

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am punctual, reliable and work well under pressure either as part of a team or as an individual. Through my work experience I have learnt that the most positive results are achieved through genuine enthusiasm and the ability to listen to peoples individual needs.

In 2019 I enrolled on a 12 week coding bootcamp at DevelopMe to change my career direction and enter the tech industry as a web developer. I had spent the previous 5-6 years writing code for Arduino (using C) as well as programming other control software, which I really enjoyed. It was this that sparked my interest in furthering my career in tech.

SKILLS

The DevelopMe bootcamp gave me a solid foundation of the following skills, in which I look forward to furthering my knowledge: HTML, CSS, Sass, JavaScript, PHP, Wordpress, Laravel, React and Redux as well as authoring tools and processes such as Git, GitHub and Gulp. In my spare time I have also been learning Vue.Js.

During my work experiences, I have gained a thorough knowledge of working with and managing people and the processes used in modelmaking, architecture, exhibition design and manufacture.

I also have experience in the aerospace industry, where I have worked to extremely tight tolerances and delivery schedules. I have signed the Official Secrets Act and have Ministry Of Defence security clearance.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

2013 - 2019

Amalgam Modelmaking Ltd

Senior Lighting and Electronics Creative - Work includes design, build and site installation of electronics and lighting in models, exhibitions and art installations. Interactive elements and lighting sequencing, programmed using Arduino, PICs, Enttec control systems. Using software such as Madmapper, Adobe After Effects, Rhino (for lighting design and layout), often having to learn new software to meet client demands for specific jobs.

2008 - 2019

Amalgam Modelmaking Ltd

Project Manager & Senior Modelmaker – Role involves overseeing projects and managing modelmakers in the workshop. Work includes traditional modelmaking skills using various workshop machinery including laser cutting and CNC. Software: AutoCAD, Rhino, SketchUp, Adobe packages.

2004 - 2008

Foster and Partners

Senior Modelmaker. Work includes laser cutting (TROTEC and VERSALASER), CNC Milling (2D and 3D). Traditional modelmaking skills using various workshop machinery. Software: Microstation v7 and v8. Millwizard for 3D CNC. Pacer for 2D CNC. Running of 3D print machines.

2003

Richard Rogers Partnership

Modelmaker. Working on various scale models of the Welsh National Assembly and other buildings. Use of CNC laser cutter.

Further work history available on request.

EDUCATION & QUALIFICATIONS

2019 DevelopMe Coding Fellowship - 12 week project-driven full-stack

web development course.

The Paintworks, Bristol

2001 - 2004 BA (Hons) Modelmaking for Design and Media

The Arts Institute at Bournemouth, Wallisdown, Poole, Dorset

1993 - 1996 BEng (hons) Mechanical Engineering

2 years completed. Subjects passed:

Thermodynamics, Fluid Mechanics, Stress Analysis, Dynamics, Manufacture, Materials science, Engineering Maths, Business of Engineering, Laboratories, Computer Programming, Engineering Design, Computer Aided Design.

University of Portsmouth

LEISURE INTERESTS

I enjoy learning new technologies, going to meet-ups and am a keen supporter of Bath Rugby club and have been for many years. I enjoy photography, kite flying and table tennis. I also very much enjoy working on my house in my spare time as well as designing and installing garden lighting systems for friends and family.

REFERENCES

Available on request.